oh yeah this is gonna be a good one
I need you guys for actionable tips that
you can take to increase the rate at
which your Forex account grows this
video is gonna be targeted towards
people who already have a Forex strategy
that is profitable or they have deemed
it profitable it proven in some way or
if you do not have a profitable system
make sure you get that subscribe button
just so that you can see I'm gonna be
slowly releasing different profitable
methods including one swing trading
method that I'm actually gonna release
this week or next week whenever I get
around to it so first of all
congratulations you have found a
profitable trading strategy or I hope
that you're very close and you're
watching this just in preparation for
when you do finally lock in that final
little bit of whatever you need to
figure out that profit there to be a
little bit more consistent I know it's a
lot of you just fluctuating a little bit
something like this this is gonna be a
great video for you either way I'm gonna
show you four actual methods that you
can take right now one of them is gonna
be a little bit harder to implement but
a couple of them are actually quite easy
and it's actually gonna increase your
speed the speed at which your account
grows let's jump into it so the first
method is you will actually trade more
now this is gonna matter depend on
whether or not you are actually able to
trade more if it's a strictly swing
trading strategy that does not work on
the lower timeframes then this will not
apply to you and you probably want to
skip ahead but I would really advise you
to back test your strategies and I can
show you guys how to back test something
like that if you do want to see how
that's done actually on training view
and how I back tested to make sure that
my started you were profitable before I
actually start a live testing them we
can jump into that some point
but you will need to go in and back test
on smaller timeframes and see if your
strategy is profitable on the smaller
timeframes because you're gonna see
these play out much more on the smaller
timeframes and you can do these maybe on
the one minute on the 5 minute if you
are already trading on the 15 minute and
you're just gonna jam out a lot more
trades now this is quite obvious when
you think about it because if you're on
average able to profit you know 1% per
trade and you start trading 3 trades a
day instead of one a day you're now
going to be making three times as much
it sounds kind of obvious but you
haven't really made me considered that
you can actually just go in and start
testing the exact same strategy on
smaller timeframes now the only problem
is gonna be that you are going to be
able to handle that speed of trading
whether or not you can do that I don't
know it's completely up to you but I do
suggest that you do look at these
smaller timeframes and look at more
pairs as another option because the more
you trade with a profitable system the
better you should do that being said
make sure you're not over trading and
putting yourself into this negative
headspace because that will really bring
you into a drawdown and do the exact
opposite of what we're doing the second
option and I really do not advise this
in a lot of my other videos but it
really is an option I'm going to tell
you how you can actually do it I'll show
you in a second here on my screen it's
going to be risk more so I'm really
advising everyone to risk 2% per trade
that being said if you want to make more
you're gonna risk more and that's not
gonna work for everyone it's gonna have
to depend on your win rate and how much
you're winning per trade so let's dive
into how we can actually check if we're
actually able to work risk more so up on
the screen here I just have a little
blurb about risk management that I wrote
about in a book that I wrote
but this is just a screen cap that I
found somewhere and it's basically
outlining how much you're going to lose
in each trade if your account is you
know for example ten thousand dollars
and you're risking 2% 1% 5% and
basically what your drawdown will be
after 15 losses ten losses five losses
whatever and what we're gonna have to
basically figure out is the likelihood
of your system to bring you into these
really negative draw downs and how bad
it's gonna be for you to come back out
of it so if you have an incredibly high
winrate then it's gonna be more okay for
you to risk higher amounts because you
know that it's gonna be unlikely for you
to hit 15 losses in a row alternatively
if you only have a 30% win rate then we
generally want to keep our risk quite
low because it's very easy for you to go
on these made major losing streaks 10
plus losing streaks so if we jump over I
have an equity curve I just search this
up here on Google and let's say I typed
in something already I typed in $1,000
and you have a 30% win rate and let's
assume it's a profitable system so
you're winning three to one of the time
actually with 30% you're gonna need a
little bit more let's say you're winning
four to one so you're your wins are four
times as big that way you're actually
gonna have a profitable system with a
30% win rate on average and number of
trades number of lines it doesn't really
matter and let's say you risk your
currently risking 1% per trade let's
start that simulation so you can see the
equity growth on average is increasing
over time now you know after a hundred
trades you're at a 80% profit with 1%
now this is a really good profitable
system I think actually three to one
might have worked fine not sure it might
have been profitable there
that being said it doesn't really matter
so what you can do is if you have a 30%
win rate then it's gonna be really risky
to increase this to 5% because currently
our maximum drawdown is 20% so we
increase this to 5% per trade then
you're gonna have to be able to handle
these 60% draw downs and generally you
might think that you can handle
something like that
but usually people start panicking after
about 20% of a drawdown so you need to
figure out for your only case what
you're gonna be able to handle mind you
the actual average now after 100 trades
is doubled the account no not doubled
the account it's 10 times the account
after 100 trades so it's extremely
profitable compared to the previous
version so you can find a balance here
for you and if you just plug in your
numbers into something like this let's
say maybe we want to do 2% now ok 30
percent maximum drawdown that seems a
little bit more fair for me considering
I don't need to follow any Forex
challenges or something like this I just
use my own capital then that's fine and
you can see ok I've tripled my account
now after a hundred trades okay that's
much better I'm happy with that I'll
show you an example of an equity curve
that I take for the strategy that I'm
currently using and you can see I just
plugged in $10,000 I have about a 50%
win rate 48 a little bit less and my
wins are about 2.5 times my losses so I
risk 1% then over basically how I've
laid this out is each line represents a
month each line represents a month with
50 trades in the month so I'm trading
about 2 trades a day ish two trades a
day ish
and on average I should end the month
with a 30% growth with that I mind you
that's obviously if I'm not making any
mistakes this is how my system works
well if I'm in the right mindset and I'm
doing things properly and the markets
are being nice to me this is this is how
my system works well and my maximum
drawdown I'm comfortable with a 14%
drawdown that's okay for me and then on
the flip side this is a four-year graph
so it was 50 it was 50 iterations over
four years is 1,600 iterations one
percent risk and you'll 11 times your
account with similar drawdown eight
percent this time so as you can see I
could alter that around a little bit I
like to keep the drawdown quite low 1%
risk so that's just how I choose to play
so the next thing you can do is actually
increase your win rate and I told you
guys there is gonna be one that's quite
difficult to do and increasing your win
rate is probably the most difficult
thing you can do but I will give you a
quick tip on how you might be able to so
I use this software called edge walk and
there's a link in the description is a
journaling software it is a paid single
time journal and I have found it very
very helpful it has increased my win
rate and it also has increased the
amount that I win when I do win and it
simply due to the fact that I'm able to
see which situations my trades perform
better in so I will notice that
sometimes the trades that are in the
trend are more likely to profit under
this this scenario over this scenario
and I can't be very specific
because you guys aren't going to
understand due to my strategy the
wording I use but I can be basically as
as general as that is I can say
under different situations I know when
the strategy is gonna work better or
worse and then I can cut out those worse
performing situations and then my win
rate goes up in terms of after that fact
now if you don't have this journal you
can use something like Excel it's just
going to take you a little bit of work
to fill out all the data and you are
gonna have to actually use some sort of
calculations to figure out which
situations work better than others and
then cut the losers from your strategy
now the fourth thing that you can do is
you can actually increase the amount
that you win when you do win and this
kind of goes hand in hand with the
previous one it is possible edge wonk
does help you in this sense they tell
you okay if you didn't take profits
would you have been more profitable if
you just let your trade ride to the
initial take profit and generally that's
what I found about myself is I was
taking profits along the way and it was
smarter for me and that's what they told
me to just ignore my trade pretty much
just let it go into the final take
profit or close to it and then just
start cutting off really quickly at the
end there and that's what's working for
me ideally so that's another way that
it's helped me out but you guys can kind
of figure this out for yourself too
generally you're gonna want to not touch
your trades if you do kind of know what
you're doing if you do kind of know
where the price will eventually go then
generally I can say it's best to not
touch your trade at all you can maybe
take one small profit over 50% of the
way there but just let the trades ride
as long as they can and you can move
your stock forward after we start
breaking levels things like this of
course but usually it's best to just let
your trades go and then your wins are
gonna actually be slightly bigger and
then your accounts gonna grow a little
bit faster it's the same idea you're
gonna be able to plug in these numbers
in the equity curve thing that I showed
you there earlier and as
our numbers grow keep plugging them in
and then see how fast you're gonna grow
your account it's gonna be super fun I
hope you guys do well and if you guys
want to learn some more later on please
hit that subscribe button I got plenty
more strategies I got plenty more
mindset stuff coming out I got plenty
more funny stuff that this is not a
really a funny video but I will come up
with something funny at some point
also join the discord I post the live
streams in there so that they're
actually hidden from the channel so you
can see the discord pings and it will
tell you when I'm going live
[Music]